Seal the room.
Eminence Tedesco.
Dean Lawrence!
How are you?
I'm well, Goffredo.
- We've missed you.
- Yes.
No doubt.
Are you well?
True.
Yes, I believe so.
Eminence Tedesco, may I?
You're welcome.
See you later, Eminence.
Bless all those
who cannot share this meal
with us
and help us, O Lord,
as we wat and drink,
to remember the hungry,
the thirsty,
the sick,
and the lonely,
and the sisters who prepared
this food for us.
Through Christ Our Lord.
Amen.
Dean!
Come.
Thank you.
And we haven't even begun yet.
Did I hear correctly,
Afghanistan?
Yes.
A marvellous testament to
the Universal Church,
So many men of different
cultures, races,
bound together
by their faith in God.
Look around you.
Notice how everyone gravitates
to their fellow countrymen.
Italians over here.
Spanish speakers there,
English there.
Yes.
French.
When we were boys
and the Tridentine Mass
was still the only true liturgy
of the world,
we would all have been
speaking Latin.
But then your fellow liberals
insisted we get rid of that
"dead" language.
Without Rome, without
the tradition of Rome...
So what, the next pope
must be Italian?
Why not?
We haven't had an Italian pope for more
than 40 years. 40 years, Tommaso.
Can you seriously imagine
the alternative?
Excuse me, I must circulate
amongst our brothers.
The abyss calls out.
Thank you, Sisters.
Dear Brothers in Christ,
at the moment of great
uncertainty,
in the history of
the Holy Church,
we must think first of
the late Holy Father,
whose brilliant pontificate
was a gift from God,
now we must ask our Lord to
send us a new Holy Father,
through the pastoral solicitude
of the cardinal fathers.
And we must pray to God for
that loving assistance,
and ask Him to guide us
to the right choice.
My God, My God, why are you
forsaken me?
And I, Irumbus Cardinal
Nakitanda,
I promise, I vow and I swear
so God will help me
and these Holy Gospels of God,
which I touch with my hand.
Out, everyone.
Cardinal brothers,
we will now proceed to
the first ballot.
You will find in front of you
your ballot paper.
On the top half is written,
"I elect as Supreme Pontiff."
Please make sure your
handwriting is legible.
I call as my witness Christ
the Lord who will be my judge
that my vote is given to
the one who, before God,
I think should be elected.
The first vote is cast for
Cardinal Tedesco.
The second vote is cast for
Cardinal Tremblay.
And finally, Cardinal Benitez.
The results of
the first ballot are...
Cardinal Adeyemi,
21 votes.
Cardinal Tedesco,
18 votes.
Cardinal Bellini,
17 votes.
Cardinal Tremblay,
16 votes.
Cardinal Lawrence, 5 votes.
Other cardinals assigned
a single vote, 31 votes
My brother cardinals,
that concludes the first ballot.
No candidate having achieved
the necessary majority
of 72 votes,
we shall adjourn for
the evening,
and resume voting in
the morning.
Thank you.
The results of the second
ballot are...
Cardinal Adeyemi,
34 votes.
Cardinal Tedesco,
25 votes.
Cardinal Bellini,
18 votes.
Cardinal Tremblay,
16 votes.
Cardinal Lawrence, 9 votes.
Cardinal Benitez, 2 votes.
My brothers, in accordance with
the Apostolic Constitution,
we proceed immediately
to the next vote.
Thank you.
The results of
the third ballot are...
Cardinal Adeyemi,
52 votes.
Cardinal Tedesco,
30 votes.
Cardinal Tremblay,
10 votes.
Cardinal Bellini...
Brothers.
Please.
Thank you.
Cardinal Bellini, 9 votes.
Cardinal Lawrence, 5 votes.
Cardinal Benitez, 4 votes.
The results of
the fifth ballot are...
Cardinal Tremblay, 40 votes.
Cardinal Tedesco,
34 votes.
Cardinal Bellini,
13 votes.
Cardinal Lawrence, 11 votes.
Cardinal Adeyemi, 9 votes.
Cardinal Benitez, 6 votes.
My brothers...
My brothers, that concludes
the fifth ballot.
No candidate having achieved
the necessary majority,
we shall resume voting
tomorrow morning.
If I may join this amiable
dialogue.
I want to remind you that
the names of eight cardinals
have been obscured.
I assume the dean can tell us
who they are?
Let them tell us themselves
here and now.
Here and now!
No, I won't do that.
Judas.
Traitor.
Well, then.
Here at last we see the result of
the doctrine of relativism
so beloved by our liberal
brothers!
A relativism that sees all
faiths and passing fancies
accorded equal weight.
So that now, when we look
around us, we see the homeland
of the Holy Roman
Catholic Church
dotted with the mosques
and minarets
of the prophet Muhammad!
We tolerate Islam in our land,
but they revile us in theirs.
We nourish them
in our homelands.
But they exterminate us.
How long will we persist in
this weakness?
They are literally at our walls
right now.
What we need now is a leader
who understands
that we are facing
a true religious war.
Do not touch me!
Yes, a religious war.
We need a leader who will
put a stop to the drift
that has gone on almost ceaselessly
for the past 50 years.
How long will we have to
persist in this weakness,
how long?
We need a leader...
The thing you're fighting is here...
inside each and every one of us,
if we give in to hate now,
if we speak of "sides"
instead of speaking
for every man and woman.
This is my first time here, amongst you,
and I suppose it will be my last.
Forgive me, but these last few days
we have shown ourselves to be small petty men,
we have seemed concerned
only with ourselves,
with Rome,
with these elections, with power.
But things are not the Church.
The Church is not tradition.
The Church is not the past.
The Church is what we do next.
We pray.
O Father, so that we may guide
and watch over Your Church.
Give to us, Your servants,
the blessings of intelligence,
truth and peace,
so that we may strive to know
Your will,
and serve You
total dedication.
For Christ our Lord.
Do you accept your canonical
election as Supreme Pontiff?
I accept.
And by what name do you
wish to be called?
Innocent.
Eminence, His Holiness
won't get robed.
With permission.
Gentlemen, let's clear the room.